

## **NGUYEN TUAN ANH**

PLC/HMI & Robot programming, Industrial/Process Engineer

#### PERSONAL PROFILE —

Gender : Male

Birthday : 01/10/1993 Marital status : Married

Nationality : Vietnamese

Country : Vietnam

### LANGUAGES -

English - Normal - TOEIC 775

Japan - Normal - JLPT N2

#### CONTACT -

**\** 0931433272

■ tuananh.bku@gmail.com

★ Ha Huy Giap, Go Vap District, Ho Chi

Minh, Vietnam

### SKILLS -

**Electrical AutoCAD** 

**Traceability System** 

Industrial Engineer

**PLC/HMI Programming** 

Electric and Automation Design

#### **OBJECTIVES** -

Hi everybody,

My name is Nguyen Tuan Anh, a young man born and raised in a poor countryside in the Central region called Quang Tri.

I graduated with a Bachelor's degree in Automation and Control Engineering from Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology and started working from 2016.

Up to now, I have more than 7 years of experience working in the field of Factory Automation, Global Manufacturing, especially the Automotive field.

In addition, I have experience working abroad such as Japan, China, Europe (Poland, Serbia...), which makes me more confident to adapt to various pressures and also new environments.

During that time, I mainly focused on 2 majors:

- · Electrical design, PLC/HMI programming.
- · NPI (New Product Introduction), launching new production line.

(For more details, please refer to below)

I have worked abroad for many years, so I hope that in the near future I will find a job in Vietnam, specifically Ho Chi Minh City, to soon stabilize my life and further develop my career path.

### CAREER INFORMATION -

Level : Team Leader / Supervisor

Salary : 1.000 - 2.000 USD

Job type : Full time

Industry : Mechanical / Auto / Automotive, Electrical / Electronics

Location : Ho Chi Minh

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Year(s) of Experiment: 7

Current Level: Experienced (Non - Manager)

04/2021 - Now: Industrial/Process Engineer - Nidec Corporation Global - Full time

Working in Nidec Shiga Technical Center(ST/C),

but most of the time is on support work at the group's factories on global, especially in China, Europe (Serbia, Poland).

Main task is to support the launch of a new production line for EPS motor of AMEC (Automotive Motor & Electronic Control Business),

#### Details:

- 1. Prepare PPAP documents: 3 major(Flow Chart, Control Plan, PFMEA), Equipment checksheet, ...
- 2. Doing Equipment Evaluation(MSA) at Phase 3 and 4 of APQP on-site.
- 3. Apply traceability system(PQM/NTRS) onsite, which is used for tracking and quality monitoring.
- 4. Improve OEE, especially Cycle time of current running line.

Skills: PQM/NTRS · Advanced Product Quality Planning (APQP) · Production Part Approval Process (PPAP) · Equipment Evaluation · Production Operations · Traceability

#### 02/2020 - 04/2021 : Standard Engineer - Nidec Corporation Global - Full time

Standardization for Global production line of NIDEC Factory.

- 1. Make format for Standard documents: Equipment Common Specifications, Maintenance, Layout, ...
- 2. Support, modify and update some applications created by VBA, JavaScripts to manage projects.
- 3. Prepare standard equipment which is used for producing Prototype samples.

Skills: Technical Standards  $\cdot$  Standards-based  $\cdot$  Visual Basic for Applications (VBA)  $\cdot$  JavaScript  $\cdot$  PLC Programming

#### 12/2017 - 02/2020 : Research and Development Engineer - Nidec Corporation Global - Full time

Design Automation machines for 5 Nidec Factories in Saigon High Tech Park, District 9.

Receiving requests from customer - Deploying concept with Mechanical team - Quoting products price, especially in Electrical Field and Software programming.

Skills: Vision System · HMI Programming · AutoCAD Electrical · Electrical Design · PLC Programming

#### 10/2016 - 12/2017: Electrical Engineering Intern - Nidec Corporation Global - Full time

Training about Factory Automation: Electrical design and PLC/HMI programming, also Robot application for Automation Line.

Especially actual experience to build a new production line at Nidec Machinery Factory in Pinghu, Zhejiang (China).

Skills: Vision System · HMI Programming · AutoCAD Electrical · Electrical Design · PLC Programming

# 03/2016 - 10/2016 : Pre Post Sales Engineer - ITD Corporation - Full time

- · Design electrical drawings using AutoCAD 2D software.
- · Creation of documentation: Product and project manuals/instructions.
- · Creation of BOM, support team Sale for bidding.

Skills: Intelligence Transportation  $\cdot$  CCTV Installation  $\cdot$  Bid Preparation  $\cdot$  AutoCAD

# **EDUCATION**

Highest Degree Level: Bachelor

Completion date 04/2016

Bachelor - Ho Chi Minh University of Technology